When I left you, we had just created this simple user interface for converting from Python to C plus
파이썬에서 C++로 변환하는 간단한 사용자 인터페이스를 만들고 있었습니다
plus using different frontier models.
다양한 프론티어 모델을 이용해서요
And I said, you know what?
그래서 제가 그랬죠
Let's make this into a proper prototype UI and let's do that.
프로토타입 UI를 만들어 봅시다 그렇게 해 보죠
So if I come back here to this Jupyter notebook, we're going to do, we're going to write a few more
다시 Jupyter 노트북으로 돌아오면 메서드를 몇 개 더 쓸 거예요
So first of all this one execute Python takes code is going to do the same slightly dangerous thing
먼저 실행 파이썬 을 코드로 이용합니다 이것과 비슷하게 약간 위험한 일을 하죠
here.
코드를 실행하세요
So again this particular prototype is really just for you.
이 프로토타입은 여러분을 위한 거예요
This is not one to share because if you share this with anybody, they will have a way to execute Python
이건 공유가 안 돼요 다른 사람과 공유하면 파이썬 코드를 여러분 박스에서 직접 실행할
code directly on your box.
방법이 생기거든요
And that would be a bad thing.
그건 나쁜 일이죠
So share should always very much be false in in this particular Gradio app.
이 특정 그래디오 앱에서 공유는 항상 거짓이어야 해요
Uh, but it's, it's a great prototype for you to work with.
하지만 작업하기에는 훌륭한 프로토타입이에요
Um, so what this does is, is execute that code.
이게 하는 일은 코드를 실행하는 거죠
And the reason there's some stuff, some gubbins around it is because we want to capture the standard
주변에 잡동사니가 있는 이유는 파이썬 코드에서 나온 표준을
out that comes from this Python code, and return it so that this becomes a function that takes code,
캡처해 반환하기 위해서입니다 코드를 취하고 실행하는 함수가 되고 결과물을 반환합니다
executes it, and returns the output because we want to display it in gradio.
그러데이션에서 디스플레이하고 싶기 때문이죠
So that's an execute Python.
그게 실행 파이썬 이죠
And now some slightly heftier code to execute C plus plus um given some code.
이제 C++를 실행하기 위한 약간 더 무거운 코드입니다 코드에 따라서요
So the first thing I do is I call that that that function we wrote a while back to actually write it
가장 먼저 할 일은 아까 만든 함수를 호출하는 겁니다 파일
out to the file optimized.
최적화에 쓰기 위해서요
Um, and then what I do is something which involves, uh, running the compile command.
제가 하는 건 컴파일 명령 실행이 포함돼 있어요
I use something called subprocess dot run, which is a way that you can, uh, have spawn a subprocess
저는 subprocess.lon이라는 것을 사용합니다. 이것은 당신이 무언가 수행하기 위해 subprocess를
to, to carry something out.
생성할 수 있어요.
Um, and that's what I do.
그게 제 일이죠
Now, you may notice this is slightly longer than before.
아까보다 약간 더 길어졌죠
I mentioned a while back what we're going to do this this, this is a really using all of the flags
아까 우리가 뭘 할 건지 언급했었죠 플래그를 모두 사용해 코드를 컴퓨터에
to make sure that the code is optimized for my computer.
맞게 최적화하는 거예요
It's actually barely scratching the surface for people that are that know all about this stuff.
이런 걸 잘 아는 사람들에겐 아직 시작에 불과해요
There are a gazillion flags that you could add in, but I.
추가할 수 있는 깃발이 정말 많아요
After a while I figured this is good enough, so we put in a bunch of flags to do this.
이 정도면 충분하다 싶어서 깃발을 많이 달았어요 Put it
Um, and um, then we run the optimized program, and then we return the we, we capture the standard
그런 다음 최적화된 프로그램을 실행하고 표준을 캡처해 그걸 반환하죠
Or if there's an error, we return standard error.
오류가 있으면 표준 오류를 리턴하고요
So that is the method to execute C plus plus code and return the response.
C++ 코드를 실행하고 응답을 반환하는 방법이죠
It's really compile and execute would be more accurate.
컴파일과 실행이 더 정확하겠죠
Um here I've just got a little CSS string because I want to do some uh, a little bit of coloring in,
여기 CSS 문자열이 있어요 왜냐하면 제가 하려는 건 약간의 색칠하기거든요 곧 보시겠지만요
um, as you will see.
비트
And then this is the extent of the user interface, that's all.
이건 사용자 인터페이스의 확장이고요
We're not doing any more coding.
코딩은 이제 안 해요
It's just this.
그냥 이거요
So let me quickly tell you, um, I've got again, I'm using the GR blocks, which is the the lower
짧게 말씀드릴게요 GR 블록을 사용하고 있어요 하위 레벨 Gadio API죠 사용자
level Gradio API that lets you have more flexibility on your user interface, not using one of radio's
인터페이스에서 더 유연성을 제공합니다 라디오의 기성품 UI를
off the shelf UIs.
쓰지 않고요
Um, you can pass in your own CSS, which is what I'm doing here.
자신만의 CSS를 통과시킬 수 있어요 저도 그렇게 하고 있죠
CSS equals this variable.
CSS는 이 변수와 같아요
Um, and that lets you do a little bit more customization.
비트를 좀 더 맞춤형으로 바꿀 수 있어요
This dot markdown gives me a nice heading at the top.
점무늬가 있어서 상단에 헤딩이 잘 나왔어요
And then I've got one, two, three, four, five rows of widgets.
그리고 위젯이 하나, 둘, 셋, 넷 다섯 줄이에요
Um you'll recognize Python code and C plus plus code.
파이썬 코드와 C++ 코드를 인식할 수 있어요
That's exactly what I had before setting the the the default value to be the pi code.
그게 제가 파이 코드로 설정하기 전에 갖고 있던 기본값이죠
Uh, then this is as before, the drop down to pick GPT or Claude.
그럼 아까처럼 GPT나 클로드를 뽑으러 내려가죠
Uh, the button to convert code.
코드 변환 버튼요
And then I've got some more buttons.
단추가 더 있어요
Python run to run Python and C plus plus CP run to run C plus plus.
파이썬 을 실행하기 위한 CP+CP+CP를 실행하는 거죠
And then I've got a Python out with Python's output CP out for the C plus plus output.
그리고 파이썬 아웃이 있습니다 파이썬의 CPOut CPOut C++ OUTPUT를 위해서요
Hopefully you're following, but if not, when you see the user interface, this is all going to be
잘 따라오셨길 바랍니다 사용자 인터페이스를 보시면 아주 명확하게
utterly clear.
보일 거예요
And then you can look back at this and you'll say, wow, that's that's so simple.
그리고 다시 보면 정말 간단하다고 생각하실 거예요
Um, so then we've got three buttons convert, Python run and C plus plus run.
버튼이 3개 있습니다 파이썬 실행과 C++ 실행이죠
So we have to say what happens when you click any of those three buttons?
버튼 3개를 누르면 어떻게 되는지 물어봐야겠네요
If you press the convert button, it's just as before.
변환 버튼을 누르면 아까와 똑같아요
It should run the optimize method function, passing in the inputs, the Python code, and the model.
메서드 함수 최적화를 실행하고 입력, 파이썬 코드와 모델을 전달하죠
The output goes to the C plus plus code, so when you press convert it will take the Python code.
결과물은 C++ 코드로 갑니다 변환을 누르면 파이썬 코드를 가져오는 거죠
It will use the model to convert it and put that into C plus plus.
모델을 이용해 변환하고 C++로 입력할 거예요. Tool karaoke, Tool karaoke.
If you press the press the Python run button it's going to execute Python with the Python code to Python
파이썬 실행 버튼을 누르면 파이썬 코드로 파이썬 아웃을 실행할 거예요
If you press C plus plus run, it's going to execute the C plus plus code with the C plus plus inputs.
C++ 실행을 누르면 C++ 코드를 실행합니다 C++ 입력을 가지고요
C plus plus output.
C 플러스 출력요
That's all there is to it.
그게 다예요
If that sounded, uh, like a like a lot of spaghetti stuff that it's, it's gonna nicely unravel and
스파게티 같은 걸 만드는 것처럼 들렸다면 이제 곧 보게 될 걸 보면 아주
be super clear when you see what you're about to see.
잘 풀리고 선명해질 거예요
Uh, let's run this.
이걸 실행하죠
Here is the user interface.
이게 사용자 인터페이스예요
Welcome to a more colorful user interface.
다채로운 사용자 인터페이스에 잘 오셨어요
Uh, so there's Python code here, C plus plus code.
파이썬 코드가 있고 C++ 코드가 있네요
And then we get to select a model convert code and we can run Python run C plus plus.
모델 변환 코드를 선택해야 합니다 파이썬을 실행하고 get C++를 실행할 수 있어요
So let's start.
그럼 시작하죠
We can press Run Python to run this code here.
이 코드를 실행하려면 파이썬 실행을 눌러요
Uh right from this user interface.
이 사용자 인터페이스에서 바로요
It's calling that exact method right now.
지금 바로 그 메서드를 호출하고 있어요
And we see the results here.
그 결과가 여기 있어요
Uh, there it is.
저기 있네요
Um, there is indeed Pi.
파이가 있긴 하죠
And it took 8.4 seconds.
8시간 걸렸어요 4초요
Uh, and we will now flip to, uh, we will now convert that to C plus.
이제 이걸 C 플러스로 변환할 거예요
Plus.
더 있어요
Here it is.
여기 있네요
And we can now run the C plus plus.
이제 C 플러스 실행할 수 있어요
And there we have it the C plus plus.
C 플러스도 있네요
You'll see that that's significantly faster than before when if I remember right it was about 0.2 seconds.
아까보다 훨씬 빨라진 걸 보실 수 있어요 제 기억이 맞는다면 0 정도였죠 2초 남았어요
Uh, and that's because we've got these extra flags to really optimize this, uh, this code.
이 코드를 최적화하는 추가 플래그가 있기 때문이죠
Um, and so you can see we are now more than 100 times faster between the two implementations.
두 가지 구현 간격이 100배 이상 빠른 걸 보실 수 있어요
And for sort of loop loopy mathy Math code, you would usually expect that a straight up compiled C
그리고 일종의 반복되는 수학 수학 코드는 일반적으로 컴파일된 C++가 이것처럼 기본적으로
plus plus, uh, compiled natively like this can be, uh, at least 100 times faster.
컴파일된다면 적어도 100배는 더 빠를 거예요.
So it's not not not too surprising, but it's a good result.
놀랍지 않은 건 아니지만 좋은 결과예요
Um, and of course, the numbers are, uh, well, they're off by a teeny bit, which is probably which
물론 비트는 아주 조금 빗나갔는데 아마도 플로팅 포인트 회전이
is all down to floating point rounding stuff.
원인일 거예요
Let's see how Claude does and just confirm.
클로드가 어떻게 하는지 보고 확인해 보죠
And let's run Claude's C plus plus code.
클로드의 C 플러스 플러스 코드를 실행해 보죠
And it's very similar, of course.
물론 아주 비슷하죠
Same number, similarly super blazingly fast.
같은 숫자지만 마찬가지로 엄청나게 빠르죠
Um, and it has generated, I'm sure, very similar uh, c plus plus code which is being compiled to
그리고 아주 유사한 C 플러스 플러스 코드를 생성합니다 제가 기대하는 동일한 머신
the same machine code I would expect.
코드에 컴파일되는 것이죠
All right.
좋아요
One more, uh, flip to the next video, and then we will run for our hard problem through here.
한 번만 더 다음 영상으로 넘기고 어려운 문제를 해결하러 달려갈게요
Uh, and then we will call it a day, but it's been.
오늘은 여기까지 하죠 오늘은 여기까지예요
I hope you've enjoyed it as much as I have.
여러분도 저만큼 즐거우셨길 바라요
This is a great a great little product.
이건 정말 좋은 제품이에요
See you in a second.
이따 봐요